Question: how much does Manulife
Vitality save you? Answer:
welcome to Question an Actuary. I'm
Promod Sharma from Taxevity. If you want
to improve your health, you don't need
Manulife Vitality. Your smartphone likely
has a step counter. You'll find lots of
free apps like Google Fit. That's a good
start and may be enough. The heart of
Manulife Vitality is life insurance and
that comes at a price that's easy to
compare. Do you really save money? If so
how much? For this analysis, we'll look at
males and females; smokers and
non-smokers; ages 30, 40, 50 and 60. That's 16
combinations. We'll look at 1 million
dollars of Term 20. We'll compare prices
with Manulife Family Term and the
marketplace.
There's more! We'll also look at the
effect of getting different coverage
amounts — 500,000, a million, five million
and 10 million — for a male nonsmoker age
40. Caveat: term rates change and other
companies are creative too. What really
matters is the premium you pay at the
time you buy for the coverage that's
right for you. Notice all the green? That
shows that for 1 million dollars of
coverage, Family Term 20 with Vitality is
better than Family Term 20, as you would
expect. It's also the cheapest Term 20
product, except at age 30.
Well done! What if you're looking for a
different amount of insurance?
This table is for a male nonsmoker age
40 and it shows the Family Term 20 with
Vitality is the cheapest choice for
coverage amounts of 500,000, a million
five million and 10 million. Buyer beware:
if you don't maintain your discount by
earning Gold status every year, you pay
the premium for Family Term 20 plus the
Vitality membership fee of two
dollars a month. Overall, Manulife
Vitality is worth considering: if you're
looking for Term 20 or Term 65; if you
like discounts; if you care about your
health; and if you get motivated by goals
and rewards. To explore your specific
situation visit www.taxevity.com/vitality
and contact us. We can provide
official illustrations and
more details. Question: how much does
Manulife Vitality save you?